<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>swarm | computational human-robot interaction lab</title>
    <link>https://CHRI-Lab.github.io/tag/swarm/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://CHRI-Lab.github.io/tag/swarm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>swarm</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Research Group in HRI in Australia (UoM, UNSW)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://CHRI-Lab.github.io/images/icon_hu02c0217b7eeb0e7fdb8b09af6bff09b6_8240_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>swarm</title>
      <link>https://CHRI-Lab.github.io/tag/swarm/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cellulo</title>
      <link>https://CHRI-Lab.github.io/project/cellulo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CHRI-Lab.github.io/project/cellulo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the Cellulo project [6], a part of the Transversal Educational Activities of the NCCR Robotics, we introduced a
new robotic platform which is small and easily deployable. A dotted pattern printed on regular paper enables the
Cellulo robots with absolute localization with a precision of 270 microns [7]. The robots also have a new
locomotion system with a drive relying on a permanent magnet to actuate coated metal balls [8]. This new drive
design allows backdrivability; i.e. it allows the robot to move and to be moved without damaging it. With this
system, we also implemented a haptic feedback modality, allowing the user to feel forces when grasping the robot
[9].
The robots are connected via Bluetooth to a master (PC or tablet) that handles the logical and computation of the
activity. The onboard PCB of the robots only allows for proceeding the localization (image capture and decoding of
the pattern) and the control of the three wheels actuation.
During two years, we developed several learning activities using the robots. The Figure for example shows the Feel
the Wind activity, in which the learners were taught that the wind was formed by air moving from with high to low
pressure points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zv6nDMQCWCo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Cellulo project, we also started to explore the use of haptic feedback for learners. Haptic feedback enables us to
render forces, but also borders, angles, or points. We developed a series of haptic capabilities and small interaction
tasks that can be included in learning activities to inform the learner [9]. We tested the haptic feedback with
children for instance in the symmetry activity, in which the child is able to formulate hypothesis on the placement
of the symmetrical shape and to verify their claims by feel haptically the shape on paper (left Figure). We also tested
with some pilot with visually impaired children who were able to explore a map of their classroom using the Cellulo
robots.
Research Perspectives for Tangible Swarm Interaction and Haptic for Learners: We are now exploring the
dynamics of the group of learners in manipulating the robots. The collaboration among learner is not always
optimal, and a challenge would be to use the swarm robots to analyses and regulate the collaboration among
learners. As these shared resource can be intelligent agents, they could rearrange themselves according to the
collaborative state of the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/g_7glQmTIVo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s3KAoQNUPZs&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tangible Human Swarm Interaction</title>
      <link>https://CHRI-Lab.github.io/prospective/undergrad/h-swarm_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://CHRI-Lab.github.io/prospective/undergrad/h-swarm_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://CHRI-Lab.github.io/img/student-projects/swarm.png&#34; alt=&#34;graph&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visuo-Motor coordination problems can impair children in  their academic achievements and in their everyday life. 
Gross visuo-motor skills, in particular, are required in a range of social and educational activities that contribute to children&amp;rsquo;s physical and cognitive development such as playing a musical instrument, ball-based sports or dancing. 
Children with visuo-motor coordination difficulties are typically diagnosed with developmental coordination disorder  or cerebral palsy and need undergo physical therapy. 
The therapy sessions are often not engaging for children and conducted individually. 
In this project, we aim to design new forms of interaction with a swarm for enhance visuo-motor coordination. We propose to develop a game that allows multiple children to play collaboratively on the same table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals--milestones&#34;&gt;Goals &amp;amp; Milestones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement the set of basic swarm behaviour using 4 Cellulo robots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate collaorative and tangible interactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Test the system with a participants. We plan ti integrate a measure of cognitive load using eye tracking data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;topics&#34;&gt;Topics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HCI, Health, Game, Swarm Robotics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skills: Python, C++, Js&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epfl.ch/labs/chili/index-html/research/cellulo/&#34;&gt;https://www.epfl.ch/labs/chili/index-html/research/cellulo/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
